公子,雨下这么大,我们找个地方躲雨吧 The rain is so heavy, let's find a place to hide from the rain.
好 OK
怎么突然来这大雨啊? Why is it raining so heavy?
是啊,雨下的,真不小 It's raining so heavy, the rain is so heavy.
衣服都湿了 My clothes are wet.
还好这儿有个庙 Fortunately, there's a temple here.
要是这个菩萨是个真人呢,该多好啊 If this Bodhisattva is a real person, it would be great.
你做的菩萨怎么会是真人呢? How can a Bodhisattva made by you be a real person?
等你娶了功名啊,天下美女多得是 When you get married, there are so many beautiful women in the world.
何必做白日梦呢? Why do you have to have a daydream?
雨夜已停啊,我们还是上路吧 The rain has stopped, let's get on the road.
徐贵,把毛笔拿给我 Xu Gui, give me the毛笔.
是 Yes
榴莲徘徊,金黄辉,谁能洗我此时心? The durian is wandering, the gold is falling. Who can wash my heart?
若得仙子花下赐,今生今世永不分 If the fairy gives it to me, this life and this world will never be separated.
月朗,你怎么也来了? Yue Lang, why are you here too?
有缘千里来相会,无缘对面不相逢 There is a chance to meet a thousand miles away, but there is no chance to meet each other.
你别生气啊,你看看这姻缘谱 Don't be angry, look at this love story.
我不要看 I don't want to look at it.
婚姻大事岂可当作儿戏啊? How can a marriage be a child's play?
我念你听啊 I'll read it for you.
许媛润娶玉仙女,两人有一夜之缘夜 Xu Yuan Run marries the fairy, they have one night.
怎么?还不错吧? How is it? Not bad?
大老爷 Master
光天化日之下,私闯民宅,作何企图 Under the bright sun, why did you break into the house?
我们是来投诉的 We are here to make a complaint.
我这又不是客栈 I'm not a guest house.
你们走错地方了 You've come to the wrong place.
在下许媛润与家仆许贵上京赶考 I'm Xu Yuan Run and my wife Xu Gui.
既然是赶考,那就不耽误了,请出吧 Since it's an exam, let's not waste time. Please leave.
大老爷,你的厅堂空着也是空着 Master, your hall is empty as well.
就让我们借住一宿嘛 Just let us stay here for one night.
借住一宿? Stay here for one night?
小意思 It's a small thing.
白天可以,晚上不行 It's fine during the day, but not at night.
为什么不行啊 Why not?
我家有个美娇女,从来没见过男人 I have a beautiful girl, but never seen a man.
算了吧,就凭我啊 Forget it, I'm the only one.
除了吃跟睡觉之外,什么都没有兴趣 Except for eating and sleeping, I'm not interested in anything.
我看你啊,就是太乖了 I think you're too good.
这小子嘛 This boy...
老大爷,请放心 Please don't worry.
晚辈一介书生,知书达理,一心只想求取功名 I'm a scholar, I only want fame.
没有别的杂念 I have no other thoughts.
但求老大爷,让晚辈跟家谱进去打个盹 But please let me have a chat with my family.
歇一会儿,也算做做好事,及个因得 Take a break, it's a good deed.
话说得好听,谁知道你心里想什么 It sounds good. Who knows what you're thinking?
恕晚辈斗胆之说,只要一书在手 Even if it's just a book,
就是仙女下凡,也不能打动晚辈的心 even if it's a fairy, it can't touch my heart.
就凭你这句话,我就放你一马 With your words, I'll let you go.
歇着吧 Take a rest.
多谢老大爷,多谢老大爷 Thank you, sir.
要规矩一点啊,隔壁有一间房间,跟我去 Be polite, there's a room next door, follow me.
是 Yes.
这回可给我逮住了吧,还什么话说 You've caught me this time. What else do you want to say?
老大爷,原谅我,我不是有意的 Please forgive me, I didn't mean it.
你无故闯进娇女的闺房,动手动脚,还有礼呀 You broke into Jiao Nui's room for no reason, and now you're doing it.
刚才说的话现在就忘了 You forgot what you said just now.
像你这种蛮口仁义道德的伪君子, Like you, a man of good morals,
我不想让你逮捕我 I won't let you get away with it.
我饶不了你 I won't let you get away with it.
老大爷饶命,老大爷饶命啊 Please forgive me, please forgive me.
爹 Dad
这种人啊,不给他点颜色看看,不知道天高地厚 This kind of person doesn't give him any respect.
跟你多说也没用,走,到衙门去讲话 It's no use talking to you. Let's go to the house and talk.
这,这千万使不得,老大爷,您开恩啊 Please don't, sir, please have mercy.
开恩?怎么,男子汉大丈夫,敢做不敢当啊 Are you afraid that Zhang Yang will ruin your future?
老大爷,您罔开一面,给晚辈留一条生路 Sir, please have mercy and spare my life.
世道临头,还死要面子,早知如此,何必当初呢 You should be ashamed of yourself. If you knew it, why did you do it?
老大爷,我,我给您跪一下 Sir, please kneel down.
嗯,好了,这次饶了你,起来 Okay, I forgive you this time. Get up.
咱们是来跟人家借宿的,不是在家,也不是住客栈 We're here to rent a room, not at home, not in a hotel.
要是不规矩,给人家赶出去啊,连歇都没地方歇 If we don't follow the rules, we'll be kicked out. There's no place to rest.
你在跟谁讲话 Who are you talking to?
跟我自己讲 I'm talking to myself.
我不是告诉你身不由己吗 Didn't I tell you not to worry about it?
这话你对别人说,可别对我说 Don't say that to me.
为什么 Why?
仙女庙的事情,你忘了啊,公子 You forgot about the fairy temple, sir.
那是仙女,我跟她开玩笑,现在是真人,我就是心里想,也不敢 That was a fairy, I was joking with her, now she's a real person, I just don't dare to think about it.
那你为什么要跑到别人房间里去啊 Then why did you go to someone else's room?
我也不知道,背后好像有人推我进去 I don't know either, but I think someone pushed me in.
脚是长在你身上,你不走,难道它会动不成啊 Your feet are growing on you, if you don't leave, will it not move?
就是说,真奇怪 It's just strange.
对了,除非啊,咱们晚上睡觉啊,绑在一起 Right, unless we sleep at night, we are tied together.
刚才跪都跪了,绑就绑吧 I was kneeling just now, so I just tied myself up.
反正啊,跑得了和尚,跑不了庙 Anyway, I can run to the monk, but I can't run to the temple.
我说的话不错吧,要不是我啊,你又要去罚跪了 I was right, if it wasn't for me, you would have to kneel down again.
冤枉,冤枉啊,什么冤枉,你一定是被它迷得神魂颠倒 You are wronged, wronged. What wronged? You must have been possessed by it.
当年啊,我习惯啊,也是跟你一样啊 At that time, I was kneeling just like you.
你搞错了,我要看书啊 You are wronged, I want to read.
救命啊 Help!
好小子 Good boy.
老大爷,这不是我的本意啊 Boss, this is not my intention.
不是你本意?难道说还是我女儿送上门来不成 It's not your intention? Do you think it's my daughter who sent you here?
不是啦,是我的公子拉我来的啦 No, it's my master who brought me here.
我好心没好报,你晚上连找我女儿两次 I'm not good for you. You come to me twice a night.
老大爷,饶命,饶命啊 Boss, please spare my life.
饶命,你一错再错 You made a mistake again.
今天,我非把你带到衙门去不可 Today, I have to take you to the government office.
大事化小,小事化无,送什么衙门,妈妈乎乎算了啦 It's not a big deal, it's not a big deal, it's not a big deal.
送什么衙门,妈妈乎乎算了啦 It's not a big deal, it's not a big deal.
什么妈妈乎乎算了,男女授受不亲 It's not a big deal, it's not a big deal.
男女授受不亲,我要到衙门去告他,强奸为谁 I'm going to go to the government office to sue him, I'm going to make him pay.
大人不计小人过 Boss, please forgive me.
什么,我还没死你就咒我死,是不是想当我死了,还管我女儿走啊,走 What, you're cursing me to die before I die, do you want to take my daughter away when I'm dead? Go.
老大爷,是他,不是我 Boss, it's him, not me.
老大爷,只要你饶了我,上高山,下游过,我都听您的吩咐 Boss, as long as you forgive me, I'll go up the mountain and down the stream.
哼,没那么便宜 It's not that cheap.
哼,可气死我了 I'm so pissed off.
我看,你就饶他一次吧 I think you should forgive him once.
怎么,你也帮他讲话 What, you want to speak for him too?
原来你们两个都同意了呢 It turns out that both of you have agreed.
了了了,坐,坐,坐 Here we go, please sit.
That's right.
你也坐嘛 Are you going to sit too?
Today is a good day for you, let's have a good drink, here, cheers!
Excuse me.
Xu Gui.
This is the best way to enter the room.
This is called a moment of spring night, worth a thousand gold.
Drink.
Master.
I, Xu Gui,
have never drunk so much.
I've never asked you to drink so much.
Okay, let's have a drink.
Xu Gui.
Why are you sleeping here?
Father.
Your son-in-law is half a son.
Why do you call him father?
Why do you call your daughter an outsider?
Father.
Wife.
Husband.
Today is our wedding day.
Why are you sighing?
Husband, you don't know.
I'm just...
You're just an ordinary woman, aren't you?
No matter how ordinary you are, I only love you.
Oh my god, what should I say?
Don't say anything.
When I get married, I'll come back to pick you up.
At that time, we were in love.
We loved each other.
We had so much wealth, so much glory.
Okay, okay, don't say anything more.
Why?
The more you say it, the more I feel sad.
Are you reluctant to leave me?
How can I leave you?
Don't you want to have a good life?
I'm just a poor woman.
I don't have the fortune to enjoy this glory.
If that's the case, why do I have to go to the exam?
I don't want any glory or fame.
I only want you.
As long as you're with me,
I'm willing to spend my life with you.
Even if I have no fame, I'm willing to spend my life with you.
Look.
How happy they are to be together.
They're just in love.
It won't last long.
We're in love.
They're just in love.
I don't want to go to the exam anymore.
I want to be with my wife forever.
That won't do.
Aren't you the one who made me suffer?
I mean, men are wise.
They should value fame.
How can they make their children happy?
I'm leaving.
Take good care of your father.
Husband.
I'll be back when I have fame.
Why are you crying?
Silly wife.
We're not leaving, are we?
If I can stay,
I'll stay here forever.
Then let's not leave.
Wife.
Your future is important.
I should encourage you to go to the exam.
I don't want to ruin your future.
Husband.
Wife.
There's no one in this world who won't go to the exam.
You can't escape from it.
You can't stay here forever.
Even if you're an immortal,
you can't stay here forever.
You're right.
I want to have fame.
I don't want to ruin my future.
Wife.
I'll never forget your kindness.
We have to say goodbye.
Let's go.
Yes.
Husband.
Uncle.
You're here at the right time.
Don't be so polite.
Don't touch me.
I'm calling you uncle.
I'm being polite to you.
Otherwise, you're going to get married.
What did you say?
If you don't believe me, go and see for yourself.
How dare you talk to me?
You bitch.
If I don't kill you today,
you won't know how I feel.
Husband.
Listen to me.
The old man told me that
Xu Yun Rui and I have a father.
So...
What?
So I promised him.
So it was that old fool's bad idea.
And that old fool,
who is now in trouble.
I'll go to that old fool.
Wait.
I don't dare to trouble you.
I found it myself.
You're still so stubborn.
Please calm down.
It clearly says that
it's a fairy.
Look.
You old fool.
It clearly says that
Xu Yun Rui married a fairy.
How can you say that?
Look.
It's a fairy.
How can it be a fairy?
So this is a dead ant.
Ridiculous.
I deserve to die.
Don't blame me.
It's all my fault.
This is not your place to talk.
Stand away from me.
Don't make me angry.
The imperial edict is here.
This is a fairy.
She's not a fairy.
She's a mortal.
She's pregnant with Xu Yun Rui.
In this case,
we ask the heaven for permission
to send the baby of the fairy
into the mortal world.
The old man under the moon
is a hero.
The fairy will never see
Xu Yun Rui again.
I resign.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
I've been a matchmaker for my whole life.
But I'm not the one to blame.
It's all my fault.
The fairy.
Young Master, it's nothing.
Young Master, please ask her.
Please ask the old man.
My husband, what's the matter?
I'm sorry.
There used to be a family here.
I don't know where they moved to.
I've lived here for decades.
I've never found a family here.
Father,
where's my wife?
She's not here.
I've been a matchmaker for ten years.
Now I've got a name.
I'm going to take my father and wife
to enjoy a luxurious life.
Why doesn't she want to see me?
I have to find her.
She can't enjoy your luxurious life.
Besides, she's suffering.
You can't see her.
I'm a great man now.
I have to see her even if I can't.
This child.
She asked me to give it to you.
She wants you to raise it well.
She wants you to forget it.
And marry another one.
Father, you go back with me.
I can't enjoy your luxurious life.
I have to suffer too.
I'm leaving.
After that,
Xu Yuan-run married Zhang Shang-shu's daughter.
Zhang Hui-yuan was his wife.
Zhang Hui-yuan had a son
named Xu Qing-shan.
He married Xu Ping-yuan,
They were brothers.
They were closer than brothers.
Xu Yuan-run and her husband
loved each other very much.
Time went by so fast.
In a blink of an eye,
ten years had passed.
Xu Ping-yuan and Xu Qing-shan,
they were brothers.
They studied in the same private school.
They admired each other very much.
They loved each other very much.
Even Qin Tai-shih,
the son of Wang Yue-bu-khan,
Qin Guan-bao,
hated them very much.
One day,
Qin Guan-bao,
because of his anger,
Xu Ping-yuan and Qin Guan-bao
argued with each other.
Qin Guan-bao
insulted Xu Ping-yuan
He was a scoundrel.
His brother, Xu Qing-shan,
in order to admire his brother,
in the chaos,
he fought with Qin Guan-bao.
Madam, bad news.
Bad news.
What is it, Xu Gui?
Master,
the eldest son and the second son
fought against Qin Guan-bao
in the school.
Qin Guan-bao was beaten to death.
What? Qin Guan-bao was beaten to death?
No.
Madam.
Madam, are you all right?
My son was beaten to death by Qin Guan-bao.
You ungrateful thing.
I sent you to school to study.
Not only did you not study well,
but you brought your brother down.
You caused such a disaster.
Go.
Come with me to Qin's residence.
Go to Chang Ming.
Father, Qin Guan-bao was beaten to death by me.
Master,
if you don't want to know,
just tell me.
Come here, child.
Mother.
Tell me.
Who beat Qin Guan-bao to death?
It was my son.
Why don't you tell me the truth, child?
Qin Guan-bao was humiliated.
I can't stand it.
It was me who beat him to death.
No. Qin Guan-bao scolded me.
It was my son.
I was so angry that I beat him to death.
You're his brother.
You brought him down.
You must have caused the disaster.
Father.
You're naughty and disobedient.
You fight with others.
You must have beaten Qin Guan-bao to death.
Yes, mother.
Ping-yuan is smart and sensible.
He won't do such a thing.
Master, don't blame him.
Qin Shan is young.
He won't do such a thing.
How can you wrong him?
You can't slander my brother.
Mother.
Isn't your brother your biological son?
Isn't it?
Father.
I'm not your biological son.
Mother.
What should we do?
Stand here.
Go.
Kill him.
He beat him to death.
He's here.
Go.
Father.
I beat him to death.
Tell me.
My son was killed by you.
Hand him over.
Yes.
No, I beat him to death.
No, it's me.
It's me.
Who beat him to death?
It's not him.
It's me.
Only those who are afraid of death
have the right to ask for death.
You two beat my son to death.
Since you want to die,
I'll let you die together.
I killed him.
It has nothing to do with my brother.
No, I killed him.
I have a way to stop you.
Where is the body?
Where is the dead body?
I'm dead.
I...
You two want to die.
I'll let you die together.
Master.
What? You didn't die?
Master, he's gone.
What?
That's ridiculous.
Could it be a monster?
Go and get him.
Yes.
Let's go.
Brother.
Xu Yuanren.
You monster.
How dare you!
You beat my son to death.
Where is the body?
I can't even take the body.
Your son is a monster.
He was beaten to death at a young age.
I caught him.
I have a way to escape.
I don't ask you for the body.
You ask me for the body.
How dare you!
Master Qin.
Where is he?
Go after him.
Hurry.
Bad news.
Master.
Madam.
I saw him run away.
Go get them.
I saw him.
Let's go.
Get him.
Take him back.
Wait.
He's a monster.
Let's throw him into the valley.
Brother.
Throw him.
Let's go.
Master.
You're so smart.
In such a short period of time,
you've become a great martial artist.
I'm impressed.
Master.
You want to go down the mountain again?
I beg you.
Please.
I want to see my mother.
Your mother is in danger.
It's not easy for an ordinary person
to reach her.
It's not easy.
No matter where I go,
as long as I'm alive,
I want to see my mother.
Master.
It's difficult.
It's not easy.
You usually teach me
to be loyal to the state
and to be loyal to others.
You taught me
to be filial to my parents
and to love the people.
I want to see my mother.
Shouldn't I?
Since you're filial,
I'll help you.
But
it's going to be difficult.
With your martial arts, I'm afraid that's not enough
I'll give you a treasure box
If you encounter any difficulty
Just call me
This treasure box will help you get out of danger
The most important thing is to have a heart
Remember, remember
Thank you, Master
Let's go
No
Master
Let's go
No
Master
I'm so hungry
Can I have a peach?
Let's go
Thank you for your help
Thank you
I'm eating a peach
May I ask who you are?
Who am I? I'm Lu Dong Bin
You don't know me?
Master Lu, I don't know where you live
Just ahead, I'll take you there
Thank you
You're so naughty
Don't block the way
I'm the Great Sage of the Seven Heavens
How dare you scold me
I'm sorry, Great Sage
I have an emergency
What emergency?
I'm looking for my mother
She's the Jade Fairy
You're looking for the Jade Fairy?
Yes, please be kind, Great Sage
No, the Jade Fairy has broken the heaven rule
If it weren't for me
she would have broken the law
What?
My mother has broken the law?
That's right
What are you doing?
Go
Stay in the gorge
Let me carry you out once you're done
I'm done
Where's my mother?
It's locked in the ten holes in the front.
Okay, I'll let you out.
Mother. Mother. Mother.
Mother.
Mother, it's me.
Child. Mother.
I thought I'd never see you again.
Child.
Mother, I miss you.
I want to be with you forever.
I won't leave you again. Mother.
Silly child.
I've made a mistake.
I want to be locked in the hole forever.
Child.
I want to get you out. Mother.
No, you can't do that.
You can't do that.
I don't care about the consequences.
I'm willing to bear the consequences alone.
No.
Child.
You can't.
Listen to me.
Master.
Mother.
Please step back.
I want to use this box to blow up this hole.
No.
Child.
You can't.
No.
I must blow it up.
Child.
You can't.
Mother.
Let's go.
No.
Where are you from?
How dare you break into the cave and kidnap the Jade Fairy?
The Jade Fairy is my mother.
Who are you?
None of your business.
Don't be rude.
Child.
He is your uncle.
Call him.
Hurry.
Uncle.
It's easy to say.
You can call him uncle.
Take him away.
No.
So you won't let my mother go.
Child.
You are my nephew.
If you can beat me, I'll let you go.
Come on.
In order to save my mother, I can't care about etiquette.
Watch this.
Don't hit me.
Child.
You don't want to fight?
Thank you.
Mother.
Let's go.
Child.
You are filial.
The world has punished you.
From now on, you can live a free life.
Child.
If you really love me, you should listen to me.
Go back and serve your old parents.
Take care of your poor brother.
No.
Mother.
Child.
I love you.
But I can't be with you.
Mother.
Why?
Go back.
Child.
I will always remember that you are filial.
I will always protect you.
Mother.
Are you Ping Yuan?
Yes.
Brother.
I'm Qing Shan.
Don't you recognize me?
Nonsense.
How can you be my brother?
Do you remember that we were chased by Qin's soldiers?
We got lost at the other side of the hill.
Maybe I'm the one to blame.
It's been more than ten years.
I've been here for the rest of my life.
I believe my brother will come back.
Brother.
Brother, let's go home.
Yu Xin.
Master.
It's cold outside.
Let's go inside.
Ping Yuan.
Master.
Brother.
Let's go home.